Tara Whitaker

Address: 57 Greenhill, Prince Arthur Rd, London, NW3 5TZ Email: twhitaker@UMXAdvisers.com

Telephone: +44 (0) 758 555 4498 Nationality: British Citizen

Tara Whitaker is a "Big 4" qualified Chartered Accountant with ten years experience in Corporate Finance, Transactions and Audit. His expertise is in helping senior decision makers understand the options and their possible outcomes in both the short and long term.

Key Skills

- Financial modelling
- Providing clarity to nonfinancial stakeholders
- Management Reporting
- Managing multiple stakeholders

- Working capital analysis
- Training and mentoring
- Risk management
- Data process design

Experience

Sept 2013 – Present UMX Advisers Limited, Director

- Worked with a major claims management company in the London Market to understand how
 their business model worked and how it could be improved. The insights gained helped to
 drive significant costs from the business.
- Review of insurance models and proposed solutions to the issues discovered.
- Creating and operating the reporting (both financial and operational) for a FMCG company.
 Additionally, managing their data and worked with their senior management team to drive insights from it.
- Worked with the head office of a large multinational restaurant group to provide aggregation and consolidation tools for their annual report. Separately improved their internal management reporting time from days to hours and improved the ease of undertaking analytical review.
- Provided Excel training to a major firm in the City.
- Working with an incubator to teach start-ups about finance and built tools to help them.

Sept 2010 – Sept 2013 KPMG, Associate Director, Strategy Group, Transactions and Restructuring Selection of major projects:

PPI Redress Calculations – a major high street bank

- Examined the bank's existing PPI customer redress calculators and assessed their inefficiency and deficiencies.
- Managed a team of modellers to create new PPI redress calculators for:
 - o Fixed rate loans, variable rate loans and chains of up to 20 of them
 - o Credit cards
 - Mortgages
 - o Overdrafts
- Drove over 1,200% improvements in efficiency in some areas and over 100% in all areas
- These calculators were created, tested and iterated over a period of 10 weeks at the peak of which over 2,000 employees in the UK and India were using them on a daily basis.
- Resulted in over 40,000 claims being processed and the bank avoided regulatory penalties.

Mis-selling and Remediation, Interest Rate Derivate Review - a major high street bank

- Engagement Manager assisting the bank's finance work stream to prepare for a Section 166 review.
- Designed process flows for the financial element of the project including customer journey scenarios and redress options.
- Reviewed and critiqued the controls environment and processes relating to the creation of redress offers.
- Created the framework in which the different population could be controlled and the means by
 which customers and contracts could move between different states. This resulted in a data
 trail, which provided the Skilled Person with comfort that data was being managed in a
 responsible manner.

Smart Meter Strategy – Big Six Energy Supplier

• For the new market of smart electric and gas meters, advised the client on the impact of possible financing options for 15m+ of these new assets. This focussed on the amount of risk our client and Meter Asset Providers were prepared to hold and how, under different scenarios, the pricing would change as the market became more mature. This in turn determined their strategy in this market and how much money they would be requesting from the Board.

Budget, Foreign Exchange Sensitivity and Comparison to Actual Tool - Waymade Healthcare PLC

• Designed and built a tool to allow the PLC for the first time to forecast their future budgets at a SKU level, over three business units and a theoretically unlimited number of acquisitions. Part of this was understanding and calculating the impact foreign exchange had, not only on the translation of profit into the functional currency, but also on demand for different lines as their foreign exchange changed their prices. Actuals were received from existing financial systems allowing a comparison to budget to be preformed - this enabled forecasts to be updated. The tool went on to be used to secure refinance from their banks.

IPO Working Capital Report - Merlin Entertainment Group PLC

• Devised and managed the build of a multi currency high-level monthly working capital model for a business with over £1bn of revenue. Enabled updates for actuals to override the model as real data became available. This was sensitised to support the Working Capital Statement.

<u>Data Centre Strategy – a major telecom provider</u>

Assisted the client to understand the supply implications of different revenue forecasts that
they were targeting. These in turn drove the need to have capacity either built or available
through a third party to meet this anticipated demand.

Group responsibilities:

- Responsible for the monthly financial management and pipeline report. This was collated from SAP.
- Delivered training courses and coaching to the group and other departments in Accounting, Business Modelling and Excel Skills
- O Appraisal manager and key member of the recruitment team

Oct 2006 - Aug 2010 Deloitte, Manager, Business Modelling Group, Corporate Finance

Selection of major projects which lasted over 12 months:

Identity and Passport Services (IPS)

- Provided core-modelling support across multiple business functions to enable Executive Directors to make informed strategic decisions and engage in £500m+ procurements.
- Created project specific models using a bottom up approach allowing IPS to conduct meaningful and commercial options analysis.
- Assisted management in presenting their case to the Home Office and Treasury.

British Telecom

- Responsible for the integrity of the financial data during major internal reorganisation.
- Standardised the technical financial shaping process for all six of BT's lines of businesses then managed the submission of their revised financials.
- Worked closely with senior management to co-ordinate the numerous iterations that moulded the financial shape of the new group.

Oct 2003 - Sept 2006 Deloitte, Assurance & Advisory - Technology Media and Telecommunications

Major clients: Equant, ITN, Aegis, Central European Media Enterprises and Virgin Mobile

- Performed statutory audits and financial consolidations for large clients involving complex issues
- Managed up to five associates at a time on large projects and led smaller audits teams of three associates.

Oct 2002 - Feb. 2003 Prague Society for International Cooperation, Prague

- Negotiated meetings with the US government for a trade delegation from the Czech Republic.
- Assisted in planning and running two conferences on multiculturalism and security, with attendances of 100 300 delegates.

June 2002 - Sept 2003 Magdalen College History Project

Created historical database to analyse Magdalen membership from 1500-1886 for demographic trends. Work was published in 2009 under Prof. Brockliss (Senior History Tutor).

Education

2003-2006	Institute of Chartered Accountants of England and Wales Chartered Accountant
1999-2002	Magdalen College, Oxford BA (Hons), Modern History, 2(ii)
1997-1999	Woodhouse College SFC A Level: Mathematics (A), Government & Politics (A), History (B) AS Level: Further Mathematics (A)
1997	GCSE: 7 A*s. 1 A. 1 B.